[Music]
okay guys
ivor myers here former member of the
hip-hop group
known as the boogie monsters now turned
pastor
evangelist and x-men yes in ancient
times the letter x was used to represent
christ that makes me
and anyone else who has accepted christ
into their lives a true
x-man okay so the world is mourning the
loss of aretha franklin
also known as lady soul the iconic
musician who started out as a gospel
recording artist
recording her first album at the age of
14 would go on to be called the queen of
soul
aretha franklin was known not only for
her music but also for her dedication
to social justice during the civil
rights movement she's going to be
greatly missed by
family friends and fans alike which
leads us to the question we're going to
be answering today
which is is aretha franklin in heaven
this is what many are now declaring
after her death and understandably so
listen no death expected or unexpected
is
ever easy to accept and many people find
comfort in the thought of an afterlife
for christians
that afterlife means eternal life in
heaven of course
if there's an afterlife if there's a
heaven for good people to go to
then what about for bad people you'll
rarely hear
anyone saying of any popular or well
liked public figure
who has passed that that person is now
in hell
looking up at us think about that for a
moment from the controversial rapper
xxxtentacion or biggie smalls or tupac
or whitney
prince michael jackson kurt cobain david
bowie
all have been declared to be in heaven
right no one wants to declare the
opposite as a possibility
and i'm not suggesting that we should
look the greatest mystery of life is
death
it is the great unknown right what
happens to a person when they die
do they go to heaven do they go to hell
or do they simply
cease to exist atheists believe that
nothing happens to a person after they
die
one recent survey found that 70 of
millennials
profess to believe in life after death
so who's right the atheist or the
millennial
as a christian i'm about to share with
you from the bible
why no one can possibly know who is in
heaven and who is in hell
okay there are two main reasons first
the reason why no one can know is
certainty who's in heaven and who's in
hell is because we
are not god and it's not our place or
position to judge
ecclesiastes 12 14 says god will bring
every work into judgment with every
secret thing
whether it be good or whether it be evil
right according to this verse
god is the one who judges because god is
the only one who is able to know the
secret things of the heart
first corinthians 4 5 says this
therefore judge
nothing before the time until the lord
come who both will bring to light the
hidden things of darkness
and will make manifest the councils of
the heart
in other words it is not in our power to
determine who is saved and who is lost
the bible tells us that god looks not as
man seeth
because man looks on the outward
appearance but god
looks on the heart look while a person
may appear to have lived a good life
we can't know that person's heart that
person's innermost thoughts
many people who appear good are living
double lives and they deceive the people
closest to them
and then there are some people who who
have done many bad things throughout
their lives and to
others they appear to be the worst of
the worst
but i want you to think about this for a
moment think about the thief on the
cross
we aren't told in the bible what this
man did
but whatever it was it was bad enough to
get him the death sentence
yet this man in his dying moments
recognized his need
and the promise was given to him that he
would be in heaven okay now
think about this let's say you lived in
that time and you knew that man but
didn't hear
about his change of heart in the last
few moments of his life
wouldn't you be surprised to see him in
heaven
and let's say that you also knew judas
you know one of the 12 disciples of
jesus who was supposed to be righteous
and holy
let's say you hadn't heard about judas's
secret betrayal of christ
wouldn't you be surprised to hear that
he was not in heaven
the bottom line is this god is a judge
not us
so for us to declare who is in heaven
and who is not
is in fact to put ourselves in the place
of god
we can't know in this life who is in
heaven and who's in hell
we will only find out the answer to that
question when we ourselves by the grace
of god
get to heaven and this is the second
reason why we cannot know the answer to
this question all right
let me explain in our liv in our living
state
right we cannot know who is saved and
who is lost because
we're not god only when we get to heaven
will we know who is there see this
brings up a crucial point
when do we get to heaven according to
the bible listen carefully
according to the bible people who get to
heaven will get there at the second
coming of jesus and not before
first thessalonians 4 16 says for the
lord himself shall descend from heaven
with a shout
with the voice of the archangel and with
the trump of god and the dead in christ
shall rise first
then we which are alive and remain shall
be caught up together with them in the
clouds
to meet the lord in the air and so
shall we ever be with the lord wherefore
comfort one another
with these words that's what the bible
says
did you catch that the dead in christ
rise when the lord himself descends
not before listen again
first corinthians 15 51 says this behold
i show you a mystery we shall not all
sleep but we shall all be changed in a
moment in the twinkling of an eye
at the last trump for the trumpet shall
sound and the dead shall be raised
incorruptible and we shall be changed
see according to the bible
death is like a sleep jesus said in john
25 verily i say unto you the hour is
coming and now is
when the dead shall hear the voice of
the son of god
and they that here shall live meaning
they're not living now
think about this if the dead are already
already in heaven why would jesus need
to come back for them
the bible tells us that the dead are not
in heaven nor in hell
but in the grave and they remain there
until jesus comes again
in other words those who will be in
heaven do not get there
until they are bodily resurrected bodily
taken there
think about this the greatest evidence
of the resurrection of jesus was an
empty tomb imagine if the body of jesus
had been found and the disciples were
running around saying jesus is in heaven
even though his body is here on earth
dead as a nail
like christianity would have gotten
nowhere it would have died out before
the first century even finished
look in the bible there were some
special cases where people were taken to
heaven
right moses and elijah both appeared to
jesus christ
and some say this is evidence that
people go straight to heaven when they
die
but look moses and elijah were taken to
heaven
as types moses died was buried
and resurrected while elijah was
translated without seeing death
so when jesus comes again those who died
in christ will be
resurrected like moses while those who
are alive will be translated like elijah
and check this out both were bodily
taken to heaven
so what does that demonstrate as long as
the body the ashes the remains are in
the grave
it is the greatest evidence that the
dead are not yet in heaven
not a nail but in the grave look even
the thief on the cross didn't go to
heaven when he died
jesus after his resurrection right three
days after he died told mary
that he had not yet ascended to his
father so the thief on the cross could
not have ascended to heaven on the day
that he died
for jesus himself had not yet ascended
so
jesus was not telling the thief verily
verily i say unto you today you will be
with me in paradise
he was saying today i'm telling you you
will be with me in paradise in the
future
okay so now someone's asking well wait a
minute what about the story of lazarus
and the rich man where the rich man dies
and goes to hell
it's important to understand that this
story was a parable
designed to teach a particular lesson
parables
are not to be taken literally this
wasn't a literal account dead people
don't go to abraham's belly
right okay so where is aretha where is
prince where is michael
where is every other person that has
ever died they
are in the grave they are dead how does
the bible describe death
ecclesiastes 9 5 says this for the
living know that they shall die but the
dead
no not anything neither have they any
more a reward
for the memory of them is forgotten also
their love
and their hatred and their envy is now
perished
neither have they any more a portion
forever
in anything that is done under the sun
right in psalm 146 verse
4 says his breath goeth forth he returns
to the earth in that very day his
thoughts
perish so in a sense the atheists have
it partially right
the dead know nothing they have no
consciousness
but they also have it wrong because the
bible teaches that the dead
will live again at the second coming of
christ
then and only then will people receive
the reward
or the punishment that's what the bible
teaches so look
we can't know why we are alive who is in
heaven
and who isn't first because we are not
god and we cannot read the secrets of
the heart
and secondly because the dead are not in
heaven
or in hell but in the grave and will
remain there
until the second coming of jesus then
and
only then will it be known who is in
heaven and who is not because then and
only then will the redeemed enter heaven
to find out in other words all who will
be in heaven
will enter it together at the same time
at the last trump aretha if she's going
to be there
it's going to be at the second coming of
christ now
you know if you want to understand more
about this subject go over to my webpage
i'll put the link in the description
below
and i'll share with you an in-depth
presentation on this very subject
thank you for watching if you like this
video subscribe
follow me on instagram at power of the
lamb ministries you can also support
this channel
by grabbing one of our x t-shirts i'll
put it in the link as well
until then x
[Music]
you